<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:identifier>10010562</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>The Voice of Prince Edward County, Vol. 2, No. 4</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:description>"Peace Speakers Request an End To Every War" - Debbie Mariner - Members of THE VOICE attend a Peace Seminar sponsored by the Richmond Council for Peace Education. / "Gene Lee Will Attend Prep School" - Donzella White - Gene Lee, a freshman at Robert R. Moton, is selected for Project A Better Chance (ABC). / "66 Class Makes Plans for Future" - Eunice Dove - The 33 seniors' plans for life after graduation from Robert R. Moton. "Know Your Candidates: Lewis Curling" - Varian Jackson - A look at Lewis Curling who is running for congressman from the Fourth Congressional District. / "Know Your Candidates: Watkins M. Abbitt" - Donzella White - A look at Watkins M. Abbitt who is seeking re-election for congressman from the Fourth Congressional District. / "Know Your Candidates: Harry F. Byrd, Jr." - Robert Booker - A look at Senator Harry F. Byrd, Jr. who was appointed after his father retired. / "Human Relations Council Elects Six New Officers" - Debbie Mariner - Mrs. Reginald O. White has been elected president of the Prince Edward Council on Human Relations. / "Summer Session" - Varian Jackson and Harold White - THE VOICE interviews superintendent Bryant Harper about the summer school session and what will be offered. / "Integrated Gathering of 4-H'ers Started in Farmville, Virginia" - Harold White - Mecklenburg competed in an integrated 4-H competition for the first time at Longwood College. / "Seminar Introduces Urban Complications" - Harold White - Harold White spent a week in Chicago studying the problems with city life as part of a seminar held by the American Friends Service Committee. / "Students And The Draft" - Patricia Gordon (reprinted from the April, 1966 issue of LIBERATION)- A column by a high school student in New York questioning the draft and the Vietnam war. / "Loyal Member Busy Supporter of County NAACP Organization" - Author Unknown - A profile of Mrs. D. A. Jones who is the chairman of the NAACP Freedom Fund drive. / "Local Prof. Will Teach at Norfolk State Next Year" - Donzella White and Philip Stockman - Dr. Marvin Shlegel, who was president of the Prince Edward Council on Human Relations, will leave Longwood College to teach at the Norfolk Division of Virginia State College. / "Editorial: What About the Average Student?" - Author Unknown - A column questioning whether the Robert R. Moton school is preparing students who are not going to college for the work world.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <dcterms:creator>Various Contributors</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>O. Jerome Jackson, editor</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:subject>African American newspapers</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Associations, institutions, etc.—African American membership</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Race discrimination—United States</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Prince Edward County (Va.)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Farmville, VA (Prince Edward County)</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:date>1966-06</dcterms:date>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The Voice of Prince Edward County</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:provenance>Hampden-Sydney College Archives &amp; Special Collections</dcterms:provenance>
   <edm:preview>http://dams.hsc.edu/files/original/b472a382d4bf90cc30e0afcc9a026eb5.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://dams.hsc.edu/items/show/720</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
