<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:identifier>10010574</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>The Voice of Prince Edward County, Vol. 2, No. 5</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:description>"PTA Elects New Leader" - Author Unknown - Edgar Latham was elected president of the Prince Edward County Parent-Teachers Association. / "Voice Staffer Goes To Citizen Camp" - Author Unknown - Phaeby Dupey, from THE VOICE, received a full scholarship to attend the Southern Appalachian Center for Education in Democracy. / "Center Begins Third Year Of Service" - Chuck Reid - The Meherrin Community and Recreational Center, off 360, is beginning its third year of service. / "Midnight Raiders Rounded Up" - Donzella White - The Board of Supervisors were found guilty of civil contempt by the U.S. Fourth Circuit Court of Appeals after issuing $180,000 in tuition grants to the parents of students in the private school. / "The Voice's Choice" - Author Unknown - THE VOICE endorses Armistead L. Boothe and William B. Sponge, Jr. / "Seminar Spotlights Arab Problems" - Robert Booker - "Robert Booker, A member of THE VOICE staff of Rice, Virginia, attended a week long seminar to study the problems of the Arab world." / "Art, Music, Dance, Offered to Youth" - Naja Griffin - A summer program of recreation and fine arts not offered in school system will be available in the districts of the county this summer. / "An Interview" - George - A mock interview with a fake "Senator Buzzard" who does not believe in the War on Poverty. / "Love" (Poem) - Phylliis Taylor - A poem written by a student at Chicago's Crane school. / "The Will To Live" (Poem) - Milton Waller - A poem written by a student at Chicago's Crane school. / "Guest Editorial: Federal Monster - Yes, When Convenient" - Dr. C.G. Gordon Moss - A piece about the Board of Supervisors and Prince Edward public meeting where the Board reduced allocation of tax funds to the public school. / "Editorial: Is This Another Attempt At Injustice - Prince Edward Style?" - Author Unknown - A column about Charles Nunnally being denied deferment from the army at the local level to continue his studies, but being granted this on appeal to the state Appeal Board in Richmond.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <dcterms:creator>Various Contributors</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>O. Jerome Jackson, editor</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:subject>African American newspapers</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Associations, institutions, etc.—African American membership</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Race discrimination—United States</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Prince Edward County (Va.)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Farmville, VA (Prince Edward County)</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:date>1966-07</dcterms:date>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The Voice of Prince Edward County</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:provenance>Hampden-Sydney College Archives &amp; Special Collections</dcterms:provenance>
   <edm:preview>http://dams.hsc.edu/files/original/054b8ac7b2e685f839e6d4c4a11d3809.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://dams.hsc.edu/items/show/732</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
