<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:identifier>10010564</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>The Voice of Prince Edward County, Vol. 2, No. 6</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:description>"Know the Candidates: William B. Spong, Jr." - Phaeby Dupey - An overview of U.S. Senate Democratic hopeful, William B. Spong, Jr. / "Know the Candidates: Lawrence M. Traylor" - Robert Booker - An overview of U.S. Senate Republican hopeful, Lawrence M. Traylor who is opposing Harry F. Byrd, Jr. / "Know the Candidates: James F. Ould, Jr." - Robert Booker - An overview of U.S. Senate Republican hopeful, James P. Ould, Jr. who is opposing William B. Spong. / "Know the Candidates: Harry F. Byrd, Jr." - Phaeby Dupey - An overview of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. / "Moton Loses Homecoming" - Ronald Mariner - Moton High may have lost their Homecoming game to Clarksville, but they enjoyed the festivities. / "Raffle and Sing" - Oscar Berryman and Edward Morton - A Raffle and Sing was held at the Virso Recreation Center to benefit the Leigh District Voters Aid Association. / "Voice Journeys to NC" - Leroy Ross - THE VOICE was invited to participate in a seminar sponsored by the American Friends Service Committee to discuss the topic: "Can War Bring Peace." / "Editorial: Reappraisal of Prince Edward Public Schools" - Author Unknown - The editor writes that although the school system is improving, the drop-out rate is high and something should be done to curb this trend. / "Editorial: South Vietnamese Out Vote Prince Edwardians" - Author Unknown - In South Vietnam 80% of the citizens voted whereas only 61% of the Black population of Prince Edward voted in the primary, the author believes these numbers should be expanded to 100%.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <dcterms:creator>Various Contributors</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Phaeby Dupey, editor</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Donzella White, editor</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:subject>African American newspapers</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Associations, institutions, etc.—African American membership</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Race discrimination—United States</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Prince Edward County (Va.)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Farmville, VA (Prince Edward County)</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:date>1966-11-04</dcterms:date>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The Voice of Prince Edward County</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:provenance>Hampden-Sydney College Archives &amp; Special Collections</dcterms:provenance>
   <edm:preview>http://dams.hsc.edu/files/original/e3a150da19e75b49519ee4ed715ed65c.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://dams.hsc.edu/items/show/722</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
