<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:identifier>10010557</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>The Voice of Prince Edward County, Vol. 2, No. 2</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:description>"State Student Conference Held in Farmville Recently" - Larry Hines - A state student conference was held in Farmville to present high school and college students with problems facing Virginia. / "Sen. Howell Urges Youth to Work for New Virginia" - Author Unknown - Senator Howell, at a state student conference held in Farmville, tells the youth to get out and vote now that there is no poll tax. / "Boothe Sets New Leadership Goal for Virginians" - Author Unknown - Armistead Boothe, who is running for United State Senate, speaks at a meeting of the Young Democratic Clubs. / "High Court Outlaws Virginia Poll Tax" - Author Unknown - The Voting Rights Law, eliminating literacy tests, and the Supreme Court ruling that poll taxes are illegal open the door for all to register to vote. / "Many Negroes Are Casualties in Viet Nam" - Harold White - Figures from the defense department show that more Black armed forces have died in Vietnam than any other United States military personnel. / "A Look at the Recreation Centers" - Donzella White and Eunice Dove - Farmville and Rice youth groups organize weekly events and look for ways to better the community. / "Boyd Challenges People to See Dignity of Men" - O. Jerome Jackson - Malcolm Boyd, playwright and Episcopalian minister, speaks in Richmond. / "The Job of a Senator" - O. Jerome Jackson - As the primary for United States Senator looms, what a Senator does is discussed. / "Editorial: Longwood Growth Challenged" - Author Unknown - Longwood College releases plans to expand. The editor expresses frustration as the Black community will be displaced and Longwood seemingly does little for their community. / "Editorial: Moton Students Handicapped" - Author Unknown - The editor feels that Robert R. Moton students are ill-equipped for college.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <dcterms:creator>Various Contributors</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>O. Jerome Jackson, editor</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:subject>African American newspapers</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Associations, institutions, etc.—African American membership</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Race discrimination—United States</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Prince Edward County (Va.)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Farmville, VA (Prince Edward County)</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:date>1966-04</dcterms:date>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The Voice of Prince Edward County</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:provenance>Hampden-Sydney College Archives &amp; Special Collections</dcterms:provenance>
   <edm:preview>http://dams.hsc.edu/files/original/5c8c52893c3e3d2f77fb737e1c895a1e.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://dams.hsc.edu/items/show/715</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
