<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:identifier>10010572</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>The Voice of Prince Edward County, Vol. 1, No. 6</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:description>"Civic Council Lists Plans in Nottoway" - Miss A. Savary - The Nottoway County committee that sparked County Negroes to desegregate...has been re-organized and renamed the Nottoway Civic Development Council and is branching out into other areas for advancement. / "Senator Morse Warns of Education Crisis in the U.S." - Author Unknown - Senator Wayne Morse met with the Virginia Teachers' Association Convention to discuss the need for investment in education as students are the country's greatest resource. / "Reading Room Marks 20th Year" - Joyce Robertson - Farmville Reading Room, a library for Blacks in the community, celebrates 20 years. / "Game, Parade Marks Moton Homecoming" - Armstead Reid and Earl Hughes - Moton students celebrate Homecoming on November 12, 1965, the first time since the schools were closed in 1958. / "Moton Eagles Lose Two" - Reginald White, Jr. - The Moton Eagles football team lose to Central of Charlotte Court House and West End High of Clarksville. / "A Teacher of Teachers Re-Visits Prince Edward" - Eunice Dove and Phaeby Dupey - Marilyn Outlaw, an instructor from Washington D.C. who taught volunteers for Operation Catch-Up, returns to instruct teachers for adult reading classes. / "Adult Reading Classes Begin in PE County" - Author Unknown - 150 people take part in the Prince Edward adult reading program. / "Student Group Performs Second Play" - Robert Booker - "The Players Group of Hampden-Sydney performed their new play, 'Black Christ,' in Lynchburg for a meeting of the Virginia College Council on Human Relations and the Virginia Student Civil Rights Committee." / "R.R. Moton High Lists Honor Roll" - Author Unknown - The end of the first grading period honor roll for Robert R. Moton. / "Moton Band Slates Plans for Year" - Chuck Reid - The first band in the history of Robert R. Moton, organized in 1964, is suffering financial problems. / "Seek Reading Classes in PE Public Schools" - Author Unknown - A request has been made by the Prince Edward County Action Group Inc. to the office of Economic Opportunity to begin remedial reading classes in the public system of Prince Edward County. / "For Their Benefit" - Author Unknown - Senator Wayne Morse urged the merging of the Virginia Teachers Association, the Black teachers' association, with the Virginia Education Association, the white teachers' group. / "Editorial: Mr. Byrd of Virginia (reprinted from the NY Times) " - Author Unknown - Harry Flood Byrd's time as a Senator comes to an end.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <dcterms:creator>Various Contributors</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Larry Hines, editor</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:subject>African American newspapers</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Associations, institutions, etc.—African American membership</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Race discrimination—United States</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Prince Edward County (Va.)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Farmville, VA (Prince Edward County)</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:date>1965-12</dcterms:date>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The Voice of Prince Edward County</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:provenance>Hampden-Sydney College Archives &amp; Special Collections</dcterms:provenance>
   <edm:preview>http://dams.hsc.edu/files/original/e0cc36b8c29eed67101a476334d6b5d0.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://dams.hsc.edu/items/show/730</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
