<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:identifier>10010566</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>The Voice of Prince Edward County, Vol. 2, No. 7</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:description>"New Industry Operates in Farmville" - Vivian Scott and Harold White - Stackpole Component Company, who came to Prince Edward in early 1966 and located its pilot plant, which employs 140 people, on Highway 460 has started work on a new plant. / "Virso Voters League" - Edward Morton and Carl Ross - The Virso Voters League, started in Spetember of 1966, is on a mission to register more voters and get them to the polls. / "Dramatic Club Journeyed to Luther Foster School" - Leroy Ross - The Robert R. Moton Drama Club attends a drama clinic at Luther H. Foster High School. / "Moton Student Publishes Poem" - Phillip Stockman - Robert Booker had three of his poems published in A BURST OF TRIUMPHS. / "Is the Job Corps for You?" - Robert Booker and Gladys Lawson - The Job Corps, made possible by the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, is explained. / "Attention Voice Readers!!" - Author Unknown - THE VOICE sponsors a gospel hour at Race Street Baptist Church to raise funds. / "Reviewing the Centennial Celebration of First Baptist" - Chuck Reid - First Baptist Church celebrates its hundred year anniversary and seventeen years of Rev. L. Francis Griffin as minister. / "County Needs Being Studied by PECAG" - Cocheyse Griffin and Debra White - Prince Edward Community Action Group, Inc. is sponsoring seven community aides to study the needs of people in the county. / "Foster Defeats Moton" - Legrant Scott and Edward Morton - Moton is defeated by Foster at the Homecoming game. / "Famous Negroes" - Varian Jackson - The first in a series of columns exploring famous Black pioneers of America. / "Editorial: The End of the Line" - Author Unknown - A plea for the Board of Supervisors to give attention to the public schools. / "Guest Editorial: The Truth Shall Make You Free" - L. Francis Griffin - A piece condemning The Farmville Herald for its biases while exploring the facts behind the Supreme Court ruling of 1954, Brown vs. Board.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <dcterms:creator>Various Contributors</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Phaeby Dupey, editor</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Donzella White, editor</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:subject>African American newspapers</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Associations, institutions, etc.—African American membership</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Race discrimination—United States</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Prince Edward County (Va.)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Farmville, VA (Prince Edward County)</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:date>1966-12</dcterms:date>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The Voice of Prince Edward County</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:provenance>Hampden-Sydney College Archives &amp; Special Collections</dcterms:provenance>
   <edm:preview>http://dams.hsc.edu/files/original/65e04f1f2fc04b6f71d82e2f06642a60.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://dams.hsc.edu/items/show/724</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
