<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:identifier>10010567</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>The Voice of Prince Edward County, Vol. 3, No. 1</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:description>"Human Relations' Youth Organize" - Philip Stockman - The Prince Edward Youth Council on Human Relations is a new organization comprised of members from Hampden-Sydney College, Longwood College, and Robert R. Moton High School. / "Supervisors Ask Midnight Raid Loot Be Returned" - Carl Eggleston and Chuckie Reid - The Board of Supervisors is appealing to those who received money from the $181,005 to voluntarily return the tuition grants. / "Youth Fellowship Group Formed" - Ronald Mariner - A Youth Fellowship Group was formed under the direction of Rev. L. F. Griffin and is made up of youth from various churches in Prince Edward County. "Moton Wins 73-58" - John Stokes - Robert R. Moton High School beats Riverview High School in basketball. / "Medicare" - Denise Mariner and Leroy Ross - Hospital and Medical Insurance through Medicare are explained. / "Myths and Realities" - Varian Jackson and Harold White - Harold White and Varian Jackson recount a American Friends Service Committee seminar they attended in Washington D.C. in December of 1966. / "Moton Wins 77-76" - John Stokes - Robert R. Moton beats West End High School of Clarksville in basketball. / "Annual Christmas Program" - Carl Ross - Robert R. Moton band and choir participate in the annual Christmas program. / "Southside Vocational School" - Gladys Lawson and Vivian Scott - The Southside Vocational School, which serves eight counties, in Crewe's offerings are detailed. / "Famous Negroes" - Varian Jackson - The life of the Moroccan explorer, Esteban, is detailed. / "My Experience at a Dance Camp" - Vonita White - Vonita White recounts her summer at Rablerny Camp for the Performing Arts in New Hope, Pennsylvania. / "Editorial: Lack of Parent's Help" - Author Unknown - A piece on how youth are more inquisitive yet still need guidance from the older generation. / "Editorial: A Need for A Pre-School Program" - Author Unknown - A call for federal aid to create a Head Start pre-school program. / "Editorial: Preparing for '67 Elections" - Author Unknown - A call for all those in the Black community to register and vote in the 1967 local elections.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <dcterms:creator>Various Contributors</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Phaeby Dupey, editor</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Donzella White, editor</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:subject>African American newspapers</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Associations, institutions, etc.—African American membership</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Race discrimination—United States</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Prince Edward County (Va.)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Farmville, VA (Prince Edward County)</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:date>1967-02</dcterms:date>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The Voice of Prince Edward County</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:provenance>Hampden-Sydney College Archives &amp; Special Collections</dcterms:provenance>
   <edm:preview>http://dams.hsc.edu/files/original/8a795a094f26f49d1d1b7ff3746d99ac.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://dams.hsc.edu/items/show/725</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
