<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:identifier>10010553</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Nova Virginiae Tabula / Amstelodami, ex officina Henrici Hondi</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:description>Amsterdam, 1630/1636; The first derivative of Smith's map of Virginia appeared in Atlas Novus in the editions of 1636, 1638, 1641, and 1644. It is the only Smith derivative with the Indian facing the Chesapeake Bay. Powhatan's Lodge appears in the upper left of the map. The families of the Amsterdam mapmakers, many of whom spent some time in London, were closely related. Jodocus Hondius (1563-1612), a Flemish engraver and instrument maker, bought plates from Mercator's family, probably in 1604. Hondius went to London about 1583, married Colette, the sister of Pieter van den Keere, in 1587, and moved to Amsterdam about 1593, establishing his publishing and bookselling firm. His daughter Elizabeth married Jan Jansson in 1612, and she helped her mother with the family firm until Colette's death in 1629. Her husband Jan later worked with her brothers, Jodocus Jr. (d.1629) and Henricus. It was from the younger Jodocus Hondius' estate that Blaeu bought 36 plates, one of which was this first derivative of Smith's map of Virginia. --From This New Founde Lande: The Henry &amp; Kaye Spalding Map Collection at Hampden-Sydney College, 2008.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:language/>
   <dcterms:creator>Hondius, Hendrik, 1597-1651</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:subject>Maps</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Chesapeake Bay Region (Md. and Va.)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Maps--Early works to 1800</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Cartographic materials</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>British North America</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:date>1630/1636</dcterms:date>
   <dcterms:type>Still Image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>Henry and Kaye Spalding Map Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:provenance>The Henry and Kaye Spalding Map Collection at Hampden-Sydney College; Image appears on pg. 25 (plate 9) of This New Founde Land, Hampden-Sydney College, Virginia, 2008</dcterms:provenance>
   <edm:preview>http://dams.hsc.edu/files/original/47ebb9d8ebe9c7a32968ac10a9f6643b.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://dams.hsc.edu/items/show/710</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
